Guide to the William S. Vickrey Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Conference Materials
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Confirmations, July-Aug. 1991 (Box 39, Folder 679)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Joint Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 680)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Letter re: Submitted Papers A-G, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 681)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Letter re: Submitted Papers H-M, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 682)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Letter re: Submitted Papers N-T, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 683)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Letter re: Submitted Papers U-Y, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 684)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Proceedings, 1990-1992 (Box 39, Folder 685)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Proposed Sessions, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 686)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Proposed Sessions, Jan. 1991 (Box 40, Folder 687)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Proposed Sessions, Feb.-April 1991 (Box 40, Folder 688)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Proposed Sessions, May-Aug. 1991 (Box 40, Folder 689)
  - American Economic Association (AEA) 1991 Annual Meeting: Rejection Letters, Aug.-Sept. 1991 (Box 40, Folder 690)
  - ATS-LRIS Analysis Conferences, July 1970 (Box 40, Folder 691)
  - The Econometric Society Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 40, Folder 692)
  - Economic and Social Studies Conference Board of Turkey Conference on "Tax Losses in Turkey and Preventative Measures", May-Oct. 1977 (Box 40, Folder 693)
    [Held in Istanbul, 25-27 Oct. 1977. See also Design of Taxes to Minimize Evasion, Box 22, Folder 366.]
  - The Fourth International Economics Conference on China, 1992-1993 (Box 40, Folder 694)
    [Held in Beijing, 10-12 Nov. 1992.]
  - FRB Conference on Auction Reform, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 695)
    [Held in Washington, D.C., 3 June 1992.]
  - Highway Finance Seminar, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 696)
    [Held at Michigan State University, 17-18 June 1957.]
  - Highway Research Board 48th Annual Meeting, 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 697)
    [Held in Washington, D.C., 13-18 July 1969.]
  - ICC Practitioners Association Annual Meeting, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 698)
    [Held at Palmer House, Chicago, Illinois, 12 May 1966.]
  - International Association of Energy Economists (IAEE) Annual Conference, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 699)
    [Held in Washington, D.C., 4-6 June 1979. See also Responsive Pricing Based on Marginal Cost as a Means of Promoting Efficient Energy Usage, Box 19, Folder 307.]
  - International Economic Association (IEA) Conferences, 1974 & 1976 (Box 41, Folder 700)
  - International Symposium "1973 Man and Transport", 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 701)
    [Held in Tokyo, Asahi Shimbun, 3-7 Sept. 1973. See also Detailed Pricing of Urban Transportation Services: The Essential Key to Efficient Urban Transportation, Box 25, Folder 421.]
  - International Symposium on Transportation Pricing, 18-19 July 1969 (Box 41, Folder 702)
    [Held at the American University, 16 June 1969.]
  - International Symposium on Transportation Pricing, 19 July-1 Aug. 1969, undated (Box 41, Folder 703)
  - MITRE Conference on Transportation, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 704)
    [Held 17-19 Sept. 1975.]
  - National Tax Association 62nd Annual Conference, Aug-Sept. 1969 (Box 41, Folder 705)
    [Held in Boston, Mass., 29 Sept.-3 Oct. 1969.]
  - New England Telephone and Telegraph Company Seminar on "Economics in the Regulated Communications Industry", Feb.-Aug. 1970 (Box 41, Folder 706)
    [Held at the Bald Peak Colony Club, Melvin Village, New Hampshire, 17-19 June 1970.]
  - Seminar on Urban Land Policy and Land Taxation in Asia, Aug-Sept. 1970 (Box 41, Folder 707)
    [Held in Taoyuan, Taiwan, Aug. 1970.]
  - Society of Automatic Engineers (SAE) Congress & Exposition, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 708)
    [Held at Cobo Hall, Detroit, Michigan, 25 Feb.-1 March 1974.]
  - TRED Conference on "The Assessment of Land Value", July 1968-July 1969 (Box 41, Folder 709)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 16-18 June 1969.]
  - TRED Conference on "The Assessment of Land Value", July 1969 (Box 41, Folder 710)
  - TRED Conference on "The Property Tax and Economic Development", 1966 (Box 42, Folder 711)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 13-15 June 1966.]
  - TRED Conference on "The Property Tax and Its Administration", 1967 (Box 42, Folder 712)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 5-8 1967.]
  - TRED Conference on "Property Taxation and the Finance of Education", 1972 (Box 42, Folder 713)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 20-22 Oct. 1972.]
  - TRED Conference on "Property Taxation and Transportation", 1968 (Box 42, Folder 714)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 17-19 June 1968.]
  - TRED Conference on "Property Taxation and Transportation", 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 715)
  - TRED Conference on "Property Taxation U.S.A.", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 716)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 14-16 June 1965.]
  - TRED Conference on "Subsidies and Other Government Spending: Effects with Special Reference to Land Prices", 1971 (Box 42, Folder 717)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 23-25 Oct. 1971.]
  - TRED Conference on "Tax Treatment of Exhaustible Resources", Feb. 1964-July 1965 (Box 42, Folder 718)
    [Held at the University of Wisconsin, 17-19 Aug. 1964.]
  - TRED Conference on "Tax Treatment of Exhaustible Resources", Aug.-Nov. 1965, undated (Box 42, Folder 719)
  - United Nations Training Workshop on the Negotiation and Regulation of Foreign Investments, Feb.-May 1975 (Box 42, Folder 720)
    [Held in Bucharest, Hungary, 26 May-20 June 1975.]
  - World Bank Urban Transport Policy and Planning Course, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 721)
    [Held at the Economic Institute of the World Bank, 14 July-22 Aug. 1980.]
- Series VI: Subject Files
  Correspondence, notes, bibliographies, papers, lists, press clippings, and other documents reflecting Vickrey's research interests and efforts to have his work published. Also includes correspondence, notes, financial records, travel arrangements, and other information about his consulting projects, often overseas. Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Airline Guide, 1968-1969 (Box 43, Folder 722)
  - Balanced Budget, Aug-Sept. 1995 (Box 43, Folder 723)
  - Bibliographies, 1988, undated (Box 43, Folder 724)
    [Entries are classified and often include comments, apparently written by Vickrey.]
  - Broadcast Networks Consulting, 1967-1970 (Box 43, Folder 725)
  - Caracas Road Pricing, 1970-1974 (Box 43, Folder 726)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1960-1992 (Box 43, Folder 727)
  - Game Theory (Box 43, Folder 728)
  - Korea, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 729)
  - Liberia (Box 43, Folder 730)
    [Includes part of draft report and notes on income tax.]
  - Liberia, 1965-1970 (Box 43, Folder 731)
  - Macro Growth (Box 43, Folder 732)
  - Publication of Public Economics: Selected Papers by William Vickrey, May-Sept. 1993 (Box 43, Folder 733)
  - Sustained Prosperity, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 734)
  - Taxes, 1960-1966, undated (Box 44, Folder 735)
    [Includes information on property taxes.]
  - Telephone Charges, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 736)
  - Theoretical Economics Inquiries, 1955-1960 (Box 44, Folder 737)
    [Vickrey's efforts to have text on Theoretical Economics published.]
  - Toll Roads, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 738)
  - Urban Transportation, 1954-1967 (Box 44, Folder 739)
  - Urban Transportation, 1969-1972 (Box 44, Folder 740)
  - Urban Transportation, 1973-1975, undated (Box 44, Folder 741)
  - Vancouver, 1970-1974 (Box 44, Folder 742)
  - Venezuela (Box 44, Folder 743)
  - Venezuela, 1975-1982 (Box 44, Folder 744)
    [Includes information on project with Carl Shoup. ]
  - Zambia, 1968-1972 (Box 45, Folder 745)
  - Zambia, 1973-1975 (Box 45, Folder 746)
- Series VII: Printed Material
  Reprints of papers written by Vickrey and his colleagues, issues of journals, and related economic ephemera. Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Vickrey, William Averaging of Income for Income Tax Purposes, June 1939 (Box 45, Folder 747)
    [Reprint from The Journal of Political Economy, Vol. XLVII, No. 3, June 1939. Developed as a result of work on the treatment of capital gains under Carl Shoup for the U.S. Treasury.]
  - Vickrey, William Defining Land Value for Taxation Purposes, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 748)
    [Reprint from The Assessment of Land Value, edited by Daniel M. Holland, The University of Wisconsin Press, Madison, Wisconsin, and London, 1970.]
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LV, No. 217, London and New York, April 1945 (Box 45, Folder 749)
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LV, No. 218-19, London and New York, June-Sept. 1945 (Box 45, Folder 750)
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LV, No. 220, London and New York, Dec. 1945 (Box 45, Folder 751)
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LVI, No. 223, London and New York, Sept. 1946 (Box 45, Folder 752)
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LVII, No. 228, London and New York, Dec. 1947 (Box 45, Folder 753)
  - The Economic Journal, Vol. LXVIII, No. 269, London and New York, March 1958 (Box 45, Folder 754)
  - Vickrey, William The Economizing of Curb Parking Space: A Suggestion for a New Approach to Parking Meters, Nov. 1954 (Box 46, Folder 755)
    [Reprint from Traffic Engineering Magazine, Nov. 1954. An early approach to traffic problems by the application of short-run marginal social cost concepts.]
  - Vickrey, William Efficient Pricing of Electric Power Service: Some Innovative Solutions, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 756)
    [Reprint from Resources and Energy, 14 (1992), pp. 157-174.]
  - European Recovery, Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XXI, No. 4, New York, NY, Jan. 1946 (Box 46, Folder 757)
  - Vickrey, William Expenditure, Capital Gains and the Basis of Progressive Taxation, Jan. 1957 (Box 46, Folder 758)
    [Reprint from "The Manchester School", Jan. 1957]
  - Bergsten, C. Fred and Kahn, Alfred E. Federal Budget After 1984, The New York Times, E17, 27 Feb. 1983 (Box 46, Folder 759)
    [ ]
  - Vickrey, William General and Specific Financing of Urban Services, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 760)
    [Reprint from Public Expenditure Decisions in the Urban Community, edited by Howard G. Schaller, Resources for the Future, Inc., Washington, D.C., 1963. See also User Charges as Alternatives to Building Taxes, Box 31, Folder 550.]
  - Hello!, Vol. 2, No. 5, 25 March 1968 (Box 46, Folder 761)
    [Published for Illinois Central Railroad commuters.]
  - In the American Tradition The Law Students Civil Rights Research Council (Box 46, Folder 762)
  - Vickrey, William An Integrated Successions Tax, Aug. 1944 (Box 46, Folder 763)
    [Reprint from TAXES--The Tax Magazine, Aug. 1944. The bequeathing power method of achieving neutrality among methods of devolution.]
  - Solow, Robert M. and Vickrey, William Land Use in a Long Narrow City, Dec. 1971 (Box 46, Folder 764)
    [Reprint from Journal of Economic Theory, Vol. 3, No. 4, Dec. 1971.]
  - Memorandum '96 Gegen kapitalorientierte Standortdebatte und Zeitdiktat bei der Europäschen Währungsunion: Arbeitsplätze--ökologischer Umbau--soziale Sicherung, 1996, (langcode="ger">German) (Box 46, Folder 765)
  - Mobilization of Manpower and Pressing the Fight for Freedom, Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XX, No. 3, New York, NY, May 1943 (Box 46, Folder 766)
  - Now!, 9 Feb. 1968 (Box 46, Folder 767)
    [Official publication of The National Welfare Rights Organization]
  - Omicron Delta Epsilon Newsletter, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 768)
    [International Honor Society in Economics]
  - Vickrey, William Pricing in Urban and Suburban Transport, May 1963 (Box 46, Folder 769)
    [Reprint from American Economic Review, Vol. VIII, No. 2, May 1963.]
  - Vickrey, William The Pricing of Urban Transportation: Economic Desiderata, Technological Possibilities, and Political Constraints, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 770)
    [Reprint from Proceedings of the Intersociety Conference on Transportation, The American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1973.]
  - Woodruff, A. M. and Ecker-Racz, L. L. Property Taxes and Land Use Patterns in Australia and New Zealand, Oct. 1975 (Box 46, Folder 771)
    [Reprint from The Tax Executive, Vol. XVIII, No. 1, Oct. 1965.]
  - Puget Sound Regional Transportation Study Newsletter, Vol. I, No. 3, May-July 1963 (Box 46, Folder 772)
  - Shaping the Economic Future, Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XXI, No. 2, New York, NY, Jan. 1945 (Box 46, Folder 773)
  - Vickrey, William Some Objections to Marginal-Cost Pricing, June 1948 (Box 46, Folder 774)
    [Reprint from The Journal of Political Economy, Vol. LVI, No. 3, June 1948. Provides answers to the objections.]
  - SPRINT: Special Police Radio Inquiry Network Police Department, City of New York, ca. 1967 (Box 46, Folder 775)
  - Ayres, B. Drummond, Jr. Sterilizing the Poor: Exploring Motives and Methods, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 776)
    [Reprint from The New York Times, 1973.]
  - A Study of the Potential for America's Cities Task Force on Economic Growth and Opportunity (Box 46, Folder 777)
  - Transportation in Wartime and the United Nations, Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XX, No. 2, New York, NY, Jan. 1943 (Box 46, Folder 778)
  - The Urban Transportation Institute Brochure, Syracuse, New York (Box 47, Folder 779)
  - Vickrey, William Why Note Chock-Full Employment?, March 1994 (Box 47, Folder 780)
    [Reprint from Atlantic Economic Journal, Vol. 22, No. 1, March 1994.]
  - World Bulletin of Friends World College, Vol. V, Sept. 1969 (Box 47, Folder 781)
  - World Organization--Economic, Political and Social, Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XXI, No. 3, New York, NY, May 1945 (Box 47, Folder 782)